Guide to the Gerhard Casper, President of Stanford University, Papers SC0672
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gerhard Casper, president of Stanford University, papers
1983-2000
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Casper, Gerhard
Stanford University. Office of the President
SC0672
200.75 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are restricted until September 1, 2021.
Biographical / Historical
Gerhard Casper is President Emeritus of Stanford University and a Senior Fellow at both the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies (FSI Stanford) and the Stanford Institute for Economic Policy Research (SIEPR). He is also the Peter and Helen Bing Professor, Emeritus, Professor of Law, Emeritus, and Professor of Political Science (by courtesy), Emeritus.
Born in 1937, Gerhard Casper grew up in Hamburg, Germany. Mr. Casper studied law at the universities of Freiburg and Hamburg, where, in 1961, he earned his first law degree. He attended Yale Law School, obtaining his Master of Laws degree in 1962. He then returned to Freiburg, where he received his doctorate in 1964.
In the fall of 1964, Mr. Casper emigrated to the United States, spending two years as Assistant Professor of Political Science at the University of California at Berkeley. In 1966, he joined the faculty of the University of Chicago Law School, and between 1979 and 1987 served as Dean of the Law School. In 1989, Mr. Casper was appointed Provost of the University of Chicago. He served as President of Stanford University from 1992-2000.
Mr. Casper has written and taught primarily in the fields of constitutional law, constitutional history, comparative law, and jurisprudence. From 1977 to 1990, he was an editor of The Supreme Court Review.
His books include a monograph on legal realism (Berlin, 1967), an empirical study of the Supreme Court’s workload (Chicago, 1976, with Richard A. Posner), an empirical study of lay judges in criminal trials (Heidelberg, 1979, with Hans Zeisel), as well as Separating Power (Cambridge, MA, 1997) concerning the separation of powers practices at the end of the 18th century in the United States. About the Stanford presidency, he wrote Cares of the University (Stanford, CA, 1997). His book, The Winds of Freedom: Addressing Challenges to the University, was published by Yale University Press in February 2014. He is also the author of numerous scholarly articles and occasional papers.
He has been elected to membership in the American Law Institute (1977) and its Council (1980-2010)—in May 2014, he received the Institute's Distinguished Service Award—, the International Academy of Comparative Law, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1980), the Order Pour le mérite for the Sciences and Arts (1993), and the American Philosophical Society (1996). During the fall of 2006, he held the Kluge Chair in American Law and Governance at the Library of Congress. He has been awarded various honorary doctorates as well as the German Great Cross of the Order of Merit with Star.
From 2000-2008, he served as a successor trustee of Yale University, from 2000-2009, as a trustee of the American Academy in Berlin, from 2000-2012, as a trustee of the Central European University in Budapest, and, from 2007-2014, as a trustee of the Committee for Economic Development. He currently serves as the chairman of the Board of the Terra Foundation for American Art and he is a member of international advisory councils at the Israel Democracy Institute (Chairman since 2014), the European University at St. Petersburg, and Koç University, Istanbul.
Mr. Casper is married to Regina Casper, M.D. Dr. Casper was a Professor of Psychiatry at the University of Chicago before taking an appointment as Professor of Psychiatry and Behavioral Science in the School of Medicine at Stanford, from which she recently retired. She is an authority in the area of depression and eating disorders.
The Caspers’ daughter, Hanna, is an employment lawyer in the San Francisco Bay Area. They have two grandchildren.
Humanities -- United States.; Humanities -- Study and teaching -- California -- Stanford.; Universities and colleges -- Finance.; Law -- Study and teaching -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Presidents.;; Casper, Gerhard; Stanford University. Office of the President; Kennedy, Donald
- President's records, 1993-1994; Accession ARCH-1996-138
  Conditions Governing Access note
  The materials are restricted until 2021.
  - Provost's Office, 1993-1994; AA 1 (Box 1)
  - Deans' Council Agendas, 1993-1994; AA 1.5.1 (Box 1)
  - Dean of the Chapel, R. Gregg (Administrative), 1993-1994; AA 1.8 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Student/Studies Issues, 1993-1994; AA 1.13 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Students, 1993-1994; AA 1.13.2 (Box 1)
  - Dean of Graduate Students, 1993-1994; AA 1.13.4 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Statistical Reports, 1993-1994; AA 2 (Box 1)
  - Emeriti, 1993-1994; AA 2.2 (Box 1)
  - Fund for Retired Faculty & Staff, 1993-1994; AA 2.2.1 (Box 1)
  - Emeritus Tea, 1993-1994; AA 2.2.2 (Box 1)
  - Tenure, Faculty Appointments, etc., 1993-1994; AA 2.3 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Joint Appointments Between Schools, 1993-1994; AA 2.3.1 (Box 1)
  - Faculty & Acad Appoint. Procedures & Policies, 1993-1994; AA 2.3.2 (Box 1)
  - Part-time Faculty, 1993-1994; AA 2.3.4 (Box 1)
  - Teaching Load Policy, 1993-1994; AA 2.6.8 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Development (Faculty Affairs Misc.), 1993-1994; AA 2.7 (Box 1)
  - Fellows of the University, 1993-1994; AA 2.9 (Box 1)
  - Visiting Faculty, 1993-1994; AA 2.12 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Annual Reports, 1993-1994; AA 2.15 (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate Issues, 1993-1994; AA 3 (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate advising Center, 1993-1994; AA 3.1 (Box 1)
  - Ratings (Academic), 1993-1994; AA 3.5 (Box 1)
  - Cultures, Ideas & Values (CIV ), 1993-1994; AA 3.5.1 (Box 1)
  - Continuing Studies, 1993-1994; AA 3.6 (Box 1)
  - Freshman Advising, 1993-1994; AA 3.7 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum, 1993-1994; AA 3.9 (Box 1)
  - Television, Cable, CH 51, etc., 1993-1994; AA 3.9.1 (Box 1)
  - Degrees/Honorary Degrees, 1993-1994; AA 3.10 (Box 1)
  - Educational Innovations, 1993-1994; AA 3.11 (Box 1)
  - Grading/Credit, Student, 1993-1994; AA 3.13 (Box 1)
  - Humanities & Sciences, School of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1 (Box 1)
  - Humanities: Special &Honors Program, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.1 (Box 1)
  - Humanities Center, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.1/2 (Box 1)
  - King Papers, (Martin Luther), 1993-1994; AA 4.1.1/3 (Box 1)
  - Jewish Studies Program, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.1/5 (Box 1)
  - Urban Studies Center, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.2 (Box 1)
  - African American Studies, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.4 (Box 1)
  - Anthropology, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.5 (Box 1)
  - Art, Dept of (Academic), 1993-1994; AA 4.1.9 (Box 1)
  - Asian Languages, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.10 (Box 1)
  - Linguistics, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.11 (Box 1)
  - Biological Sciences, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.12 (Box 1)
  - Chemistry, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.13 (Box 1)
  - Classics, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.14 (Box 1)
  - Communication, Dept of (incl. Knight Fellowships), 1993-1994; AA 4.1.15 (Box 1)
  - Computer Science, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.17 (Box 1)
  - Drama, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.18 (Box 1)
  - Economics, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.20 (Box 1)
  - Center for Economic Policy Research (CEPR), 1993-1994; AA 4.1.20/1 (Box 1)
  - English, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.21 (Box 1)
  - French & Italian, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.22 (Box 1)
  - German, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.24 (Box 1)
  - History, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.25 (Box 1)
  - Human Biology,Program in, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.26 (Box 1)
  - Mathematics, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.27 (Box 2)
  - Hopkins Marine Station (HMS), 1993-1994; AA 4.1.28 (Box 2)
  - Music, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.29 (Box 2)
  - Athletics, Phy Education & Recreation, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.30 (Box 2)
  - Football Games, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.30/1 (Box 2)
  - Rose Bowl, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.30/2 (Box 2)
  - Philosophy, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.32 (Box 2)
  - Physics, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.33 (Box 2)
  - Political Science, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.34 (Box 2)
  - Psychology, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.35 (Box 2)
  - Public Policy Program, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.36 (Box 2)
  - Slavic Languages/Literature, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.38 (Box 2)
  - Sociology, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.40 (Box 2)
  - Spanish & Portuguese, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.41 (Box 2)
  - Statistics, Dept of, 1993-1994; AA 4.1.42 (Box 2)
  - Religious Studies, Dept of (Strictly Academic), 1993-1994; AA 4.1.47 (Box 2)
  - Graduate School of Business (GSB) (Academic), 1993-1994; AA 4.2 (Box 2)
  - Earth Sciences, School of, 1993-1994; AA 4.3 (Box 2)
  - Petroleum Engineering, 1993-1994; AA 4.3.4 (Box 2)
  - Engineering, School of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4 (Box 2)
  - Aeronautics/Astronauts, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.1 (Box 2)
  - Telecommunications, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.1/1 (Box 2)
  - Electrical Engineering, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.5 (Box 2)
  - Industrial Engineering/Management, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.6 (Box 2)
  - Materials Science Engineering, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.8 (Box 2)
  - Mechanical Engineering, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.9 (Box 2)
  - Operations Research, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.10 (Box 2)
  - Chemical Engineering, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.13 (Box 2)
  - Center for Teaching & Learning, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.20 (Box 2)
  - Electrical Engineering, Dept. of, 1993-1994; AA 4.4.5 (Box 2)
  - Education, School of, 1993-1994; AA 4.5 (Box 2)
  - School of Medicine, 1993-1994; AA 4.6 (Box 2)
  - Medical Center Clinics (Eliminated file), 1993-1994; AA 4.6.7 (Box 2)
  - Howard Hughes Medical Institute, 1993-1994; AA 4.6.8 (Box 2)
  - Health Services Administration, 1993-1994; AA 4.6.9 (Box 2)
  - Patient Relations, 1993-1994; AA 4.6.13 (Box 2)
  - Hoover Institution, General, 1993-1994; AA 4.9 (Box 3)
  - Hoover Inst - Board of Overseers, 1993-1994; AA 4.9.1 (Box 3)
  - Japanese Studies at Stanford, 1993-1994; AA 4.10.2 (Box 3)
  - Center for Intl Security & Arms Control, 1993-1994; AA 4.10.6 (Box 3)
  - Committee for Int'l Studies at ST, 1993-1994; AA 4.10.6/3 (Box 3)
  - Latin American Studies, Center for, 1993-1994; AA 4.11 (Box 3)
  - Libraries Stanford, general catch-all, 1993-1994; AA 4.12 (Box 3)
  - Advisory Council for Libraries & Information, 1993-1994; AA 4.12.2 (Box 3)
  - Associates of Stanford Univ Libraries, 1993-1994; AA 4.12.3 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, 1993-1994; AA 4.13 (Box 3)
  - Institute Mathmatical Studies in the Social Sciences, 1993-1994; AA 4.14 (Box 3)
  - Law, School of, 1993-1994; AA 4.15 (Box 3)
  - Stanford University Medical Center, 1993-1994; AA 4.17 (Box 3)
  - Stanford University Hospital, 1993-1994; AA 4.17.1 (Box 3)
  - Stanford University Hospital Board of Directors, 1993-1994; AA 4.17.2 (Box 3)
  - Lucille Packard Childrens Hospital, 1993-1994; AA 4.17.5/1 (Box 3)
  - Animal Rights Issues (Comparative Medicine), 1993-1994; AA 4.17.6 (Box 3)
  - Information Technology Services (ITSS), 1993-1994; AA 4.22 (Box 3)
  - Information Resources Vice President, 1993-1994; AA 4.22.2 (Box 3)
  - Awards & Prizes, Miscellaneous, 1993-1994; AA 5 (Box 4)
  - Grants, Miscellaneous, 1993-1994; AA 6 (Box 4)
  - Scholarships, Miscellaneous, 1993-1994; AA 7 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships, Misc/General Information, 1993-1994; AA 8 (Box 4)
  - Fulbright Fellowship, 1993-1994; AA 8.16 (Box 4)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Fellowship, 1993-1994; AA 8.17 (Box 4)
  - Knight Fellowships, 1993-1994; AA 8.25 (Box 4)
  - Tanner Lectures, 1993-1994; AA 9.19 (Box 4)
  - Faculty, Profs, Chairs, Visitors, 1993-1994; AA 10 (Box 4)
  - Visiting Professorships Misc., 1993-1994; AA 10.59 (Box 4)
  - Stanford Miscellaneous, 1993-1994; AD 1 (Box 4)
  - Historical Society, Stanford, 1993-1994; AD 1.2 (Box 4)
  - Student, Admin/Faculty Relations, 1993-1994; AD 1.4 (Box 4)
  - Stanford Statistics, Misc, 1993-1994; AD 1.5 (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports, Admin and Acad, 1993-1994; AD 1.6.3 (Box 4)
  - Admin. Reorganization, 1993-1994; AD 1.6.4 (Box 4)
  - University Policy, 1993-1994; AD 2 (Box 4)
  - Bicycles (Safety, Paths, etc.), 1993-1994; AD 2.1 (Box 4)
  - Recruiting, On-Campus, Military, 1993-1994; AD 2.3 (Box 4)
  - Stanford Mascot/Symbol, 1993-1994; AD 2.7 (Box 4)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Fund, 1993-1994; AD 2.10.4/116 (Box 4)
  - Disability Resources, 1993-1994; AD 2.11 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Harassment/Assault Policy, 1993-1994; AD 2.15/2 (Box 4)
  - Univ Address Lists/Policy for use of, 1993-1994; AD 3.1 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Handbook, 1993-1994; AD 3.7 (Box 4)
  - Fundamental Standard (Honor Code), 1993-1994; AD 3.10 (Box 4)
  - Speeches/Lectures, 1993-1994; AD 3.22 (Box 4)
  - President's Office (More personal GC stuff), 1993-1994; AD 4 (Box 4)
  - President, 1993-1994; AD 4.1 (Box 4)
  - Presidential Powers, 1993-1994; AD 4.2 (Box 4)
  - President's House, Staff, Car, 1993-1994; AD 4.7 (Box 4)
  - Cabinet, University (Lowell Price), 1993-1994; AD 4.13 (Box 4)
  - Academic Secretary, 1993-1994; AD 4.14 (Box 5)
  - Legal (University Counsel), 1993-1994; AD 4.19 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, General (when all else fails), 1993-1994; AD 4.20 (Box 5)
  - News Clippings/Editorials, 1993-1994; AD 4.20.1 (Box 5)
  - Condolence Letters, 1993-1994; AD 4.20.2 (Box 5)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1993-1994; AD 4.20.3 (Box 5)
  - Invitations, 1993-1994; AD 4.20.4 (Box 5)
  - Invitations (General, non-specific), 1993-1994; AD 4.20.4/2 (Box 5)
  - Nonsense, 1993-1994; AD 4.20.5 (Box 5)
  - Recommendation Letters, Routine (Search), 1993-1994; AD 4.20.6 (Box 5)
  - Recommendation Letters, Students, 1993-1994; AD 4.20.6/1 (Box 5)
  - Solicitations (General) Misc requests, favors, etc., 1993-1994; AD 4.20.8 (Box 5)
  - Communications, University (T. Shepard), 1993-1994; AD 4.22 (Box 6)
  - Ombudsman, 1993-1994; AD 6 (Box 6)
  - Legal Problems & Services, 1993-1994; AD 7 (Box 6)
  - Campus Disruptions/Demonstrations, 1993-1994; AD 7.2 (Box 6)
  - Dean of Students, Case Numbers, Discipline, 1993-1994; AD 7.2.5 (Box 6)
  - Discipline, Student, Dean of Student Cases, 1993-1994; AD 7.2.7 (Box 6)
  - Founding Grant, 1993-1994; AD 7.6 (Box 6)
  - Admissions, 1993-1994; AD 8.1 (Box 6)
  - Admissions Policy, 1993-1994; AD 8.1.1 (Box 6)
  - Admissions Cases, 1993-1994; AD 8.1.2 (Box 6)
  - Career Planning and Placement Center, 1993-1994; AD 8.7 (Box 6)
  - Student Affairs, Dean of, 1993-1994; AD 8.8 (Box 6)
  - Student Services & Special Services Office, 1993-1994; AD 8.8.2 (Box 6)
  - Policy on Discrimination, 1993-1994; AD 8.8.3 (Box 6)
  - Exchange Programs, 1993-1994; AD 8.10 (Box 6)
  - Stanford in Washington, D.C., 1993-1994; AD 8.10.1 (Box 6)
  - Overseas Studies Programs, Misc., 1993-1994; AD 8.11 (Box 6)
  - Stanford in Britain, 1993-1994; AD 8.11.2 (Box 6)
  - Stanford in France (Tours), 1993-1994; AD 8.11.3 (Box 6)
  - Stanford in Germany (Berlin/Bonn), 1993-1994; AD 8.11.4/2 (Box 6)
  - Stanford Center in Japan, 1993-1994; AD 8.11.6 (Box 6)
  - Financial Aid, 1993-1994; AD 8.12 (Box 6)
  - Student Loans, 1993-1994; AD 8.12.1 (Box 6)
  - Housing, Faculty, Staff, Emeriti, 1993-1994; AD 8.18 (Box 6)
  - Housing Office, Misc. Reports, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.1 (Box 6)
  - Hanna Honeycomb House, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.2 (Box 7)
  - Buck Estate House, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.4 (Box 7)
  - Escondido Village, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.7 (Box 7)
  - Fraternities/Sororities, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.8 (Box 7)
  - Housing & Dining Services, Student, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.11 (Box 7)
  - Residence Halls, Staff, Fellows, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.12 (Box 7)
  - Residential Education, 1993-1994; AD 8.18.13 (Box 7)
  - Registrar, Bursar, 1993-1994; AD 8.21 (Box 7)
  - Minorities, 1993-1994; AD 9 (Box 7)
  - Black Affairs, students, 1993-1994; AD 9.1 (Box 7)
  - Chicano Affairs, 1993-1994; AD 9.2 (Box 7)
  - Grape Boycott Issue, 1993-1994; AD 9.2.1 (Box 7)
  - American Indian Affairs, 1993-1994; AD 9.3 (Box 7)
  - Multicultural Development, Office of, 1993-1994; AD 9.6 (Box 7)
  - Affirmative Action, Student, 1993-1994; AD 9.6.3 (Box 7)
  - OUT at Stanford, 1993-1994; AD 9.6.4 (Box 7)
  - Personnel Services,includ Fac/Staff/Union workers, 1993-1994; AD 10 (Box 7)
  - Employment Inquiries & Request (other, see personnel), 1993-1994; AD 10.1 (Box 7)
  - Management Development Program, 1993-1994; AD 10.2 (Box 7)
  - Mentoring Program, 1993-1994; AD 10.4 (Box 7)
  - Committee for Outdoor Art, 1993-1994; AD 10.7.4 (Box 7)
  - Childrens Community Center, Stanford (Day Care), 1993-1994; AD 10.7.5 (Box 7)
  - Families, Children & Youth, Stanford Center-Study of, 1993-1994; AD 10.7.6 (Box 7)
  - United Stanford Employees (USE), 1993-1994; AD 10.7.8 (Box 7)
  - Personnel Policies/Hiring Practices, 1993-1994; AD 10.8 (Box 7)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.3 (Box 7)
  - Faculty, Staff Fringe Benefits, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.9 (Box 7)
  - Faculty Staff Grievance Procedures, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.10 (Box 7)
  - Grievance Issues-Faculty/Staff, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.10/1 (Box 8)
  - Grievance Issues-Student, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.10/3 (Box 8)
  - Retirement, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.17 (Box 8)
  - Early Retirement, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.17/1 (Box 8)
  - TIAA/CREFF Prudential, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.17/3 (Box 8)
  - Salaries, 1993-1994; AD 10.8.19 (Box 8)
  - Travel (policy), 1993-1994; AD 10.8.21 (Box 8)
  - Archives, 1993-1994; AD 11.1 (Box 8)
  - Food Service, 1993-1994; AD 11.3 (Box 8)
  - Operations & Maintenance, 1993-1994; AD 11.4 (Box 8)
  - Environmental Health & Safety, SU, 1993-1994; AD 11.4.1 (Box 8)
  - Police Services/Campus Security, 1993-1994; AD 11.6 (Box 8)
  - Commencement, 1993-1994; AD 11.7.2 (Box 8)
  - Commencement Speakers, 1993-1994; AD 11.7.2/1 (Box 8)
  - Dedications, 1993-1994; AD 11.7.4 (Box 8)
  - Founders Day, 1993-1994; AD 11.7.6 (Box 8)
  - Freshman Orientation (Misc Freshman Issues), 1993-1994; AD 11.7.7 (Box 8)
  - Publications (Media all forms, external), 1993-1994; AD 11.8 (Box 8)
  - Copyright policy, 1993-1994; AD 11.8.1 (Box 8)
  - Stanford University Press, 1993-1994; AD 11.8.9 (Box 8)
  - Surveys, Questionnaires, 1993-1994; AD 11.8.10 (Box 8)
  - Media, all forms, Stanford (Internal), 1993-1994; AD 11.8.11 (Box 8)
  - Stanford Observer, 1993-1994; AD 11.8.11/3 (Box 8)
  - Business & Finance, 1993-1994; AD 12.2 (Box 8)
  - Business & Finance (CFO),VP for, 1993-1994; AD 12.2/1 (Box 8)
  - VP for Finance, 1993-1994; AD 12.2/2 (Box 8)
  - Administrative Resources, 1993-1994; AD 12.2/3 (Box 8)
  - VP of Human Resources, 1993-1994; AD 12.2/4 (Box 8)
  - Stanford Management Company, 1993-1994; AD 12.3 (Box 8)
  - Auditing, Internal, 1993-1994; AD 12.4 (Box 8)
  - Budget (Budget Group), 1993-1994; AD 12.5 (Box 8)
  - VP of Mgmt. & Director of Univ Budgets, 1993-1994; AD 12.5.1 (Box 8)
  - Tuition, 1993-1994; AD 12.5.4 (Box 8)
  - Conflict of Interest/Consulting Policy, 1993-1994; AD 12.7.1 (Box 8)
  - Insurance Risk Management, 1993-1994; AD 12.8 (Box 8)
  - Environmental Health & Safety, 1993-1994; AD 12.8.1 (Box 8)
  - Development Office Misc. (Big picture planning), 1993-1994; AD 12.10.1 (Box 8)
  - Medical Center Fundraising, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.3 (Box 9)
  - Annual Fund, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.3/4 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Gift Processing, 1993-1994; AD12.10.3/5-1 (Box 9)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.3/5-10 (Box 9)
  - Weingart Foundation (Sol Price), 1993-1994; AD 12.10.3/5-39 (Box 9)
  - Carroll J. Roush Fund, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.3/5-40 (Box 9)
  - Scaife Family Gifts, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.3/5-42 (Box 9)
  - Terman, Dr./Mrs. F.E., 1993-1994; AD 12.10.3/5-47 (Box 9)
  - Foundations & Corporations, Miscellaneous, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.4 (Box 9)
  - Crossett Fund, Elizabeth Rankin, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.4/52 (Box 9)
  - Crown Zellerbach Foundation, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.4/53 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.4/71 (Box 9)
  - Irvine, James Foundation, 1993-1994; AD 12.10.4/103 (Box 9)
  - Corporations, Mics., 1993-1994; AD 12.10.5 (Box 9)
  - Technology Licensing/Patents/Copyrights, 1993-1994; AD 12.11 (Box 9)
  - Real Estate Programs, 1993-1994; AD 12.13 (Box 9)
  - Land and Buildings, general catch-all, 1993-1994; AD 12.14 (Box 9)
  - Land Use & Facilities, Policy, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.1 (Box 9)
  - Earthquake, 1989, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.1/2 (Box 9)
  - Buildings, Space, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7 (Box 9)
  - Art Galleries and Museums, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/1 (Box 9)
  - Athletics (Space, Facilities), 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/2 (Box 10)
  - Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/16 (Box 10)
  - Facilities & Services (incl. Facilities Planning ), 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/29 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Club, The Stanford, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/30 (Box 10)
  - Science & Engineering Quad (SEQ) Physical, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/31 (Box 10)
  - Humanities & Sciences (space), 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/39 (Box 10)
  - Jasper Ridge Biological Experimental Area, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/43 (Box 10)
  - Campus Ministries (Memorial Church), 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/50 (Box 10)
  - Parking & Transportation, 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/53 (Box 10)
  - Tresidder Memorial Union (TMU), 1993-1994; AD 12.14.7/64 (Box 10)
  - Accounting (Controller's Office), 1993-1994; AD 12.15 (Box 10)
  - Visitors (to campus), 1993-1994; AD 13.10 (Box 10)
  - Conferences, Miscellaneous, 1993-1994; AD 13.10.1 (Box 10)
  - Foreign Visitors, 1993-1994; AD 13.10.3 (Box 10)
  - Earth Sciences, Advisory Board, 1993-1994; AD 13.10.5/2 (Box 10)
  - School of Engineering Advisory Council, 1993-1994; AD 13.10.5/7 (Box 10)
  - Graduate School of Business Advisory Board, 1993-1994; AD 13.10.5/8 (Box 10)
  - Alumni Relations (specific individuals, not groups), 1993-1994; AL 1 (Box 10)
  - Letters to Alum/Students, 1993-1994; AL 1.2 (Box 10)
  - Alumni College, 1993-1994; AL 1.6 (Box 10)
  - Reunion/Homecoming/Alumni Events, 1993-1994; AL 1.7 (Box 10)
  - Class Reunions, 1993-1994; AL 1.8 (Box 10)
  - Stanford Magazine,The, 1993-1994; AL 1.12 (Box 10)
  - Stanford Associates, 1993-1994; AL 2 (Box 10)
  - Alumni Association, All groups except Bowman, 1993-1994; AL 3 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, BoT, 1993-1994; B 1 (Box 10)
  - Senate of the Acad Council (Miscellaneous), 1993-1994; C 2 (Box 10)
  - Academic Council: Senate Report # (see Committee), 1993-1994; C 2.4 (Box 11)
  - Advisory Board, 1993-1994; C 3 (Box 11)
  - Steering Committee (STC), 1993-1994; C 4.1 (Box 11)
  - Commission on Technology in Teaching & Learning, 1993-1994; C 5.7.2 (Box 11)
  - United States Government Relations, 1993-1994; G 3 (Box 11)
  - Foreign Government Relations, 1993-1994; G 5 (Box 11)
  - Council on Foreign Relations/Pacific Council on Int'l Policy, 1993-1994; G 10 (Box 11)
  - Medical Center Task Force, 1993-1994; SHS 1 (Box 11)
  - Stanford Health System General, 1993-1994; SHS 2 (Box 11)
  - Administration - SHS, 1993-1994; SHS 3 (Box 11)
  - Some strange, uncoded material left over from '93, 1993-1994; No code (Box 11)
  - archive., 1993-1994 (Box not specified)
  - Miscellaneous & Ad Hoc Organization, 1993-1994; O 1 (Box 12)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education(Kennedy stuff that, 1993-1994; CFAE (Box 12)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), 1993-1994; O 3.44 (Box 12)
  - Pacific-Ten Conference (PAC-10), 1993-1994; O 3.47 (Box 12)
  - California Business Higher Education Forum, 1993-1994; O 3.56 (Box 13)
  - Universities & Colleges, Misc., 1993-1994; O 8 (Box 13)
  - Association of American Universities, 1993-1994; O 8.7 (Box 13)
  - Western Assoc. of Schools & Colleges (WASC), 1993-1994; O 8.52 (Box 13)
  - Bay Area Economic Forum/Bay Area Council, 1993-1994; O 11 (Box 13)
  - German American Academic Council Foundation (GAAC), 1993-1994; O 14 (Box 14)
  - Research, Miscellaneous, 1993-1994; R 0 (Box 14)
  - Institute for International Studies, 1993-1994; R 1.12 (Box 14)